Email: nvredding2@gmail.com github.com/nigelvr Mobile: +1-343-322-8659

Professional Summary

I am a highly motivated and skilled software developer with five years of professional experience. I have a wide range of technical experience, including working with trading systems and embedded development. I would like to grow in to a technical leadership role.

EDUCATION

Carleton University

Ottawa, On

BSc Mathematics; GPA: 11.92/12

Fall 2010 - January 2015

University of Ottawa

Ottawa, On

MSc Mathematics

Fall 2015 - Summer 2017

EXPERIENCE

SociVolta

Montreal, Qc

Senior Software Developer

November 2019 - April 2023

- Development of a key trading tool which provided the research team with trading-signal data. This tool was also used in production for trading. We used Python and Pandas for manipulating large amounts of market data.
- Worked across various teams (cloud operations, research, data) to address operational issues
- Worked with the CEO, COO and business analysts to understand business requirements
- o Development of ETL jobs for market data and automated jobs for executing market transactions: Python, Apache Airflow
- Development of Jenkins CI/CD jobs for building our containers
- Helped the company get set up on the AWS platform: EC2, Lambda, Jenkins, Docker, Apache Airflow

ZeligSoft

Gatineau, Qc

Software Developer

January 2018 - November 2019

- Development of code-generation tool which translated and interface description language (IDL) into Python stubs: C, Python, OMG IDL
- Development and maintenance of OpenSplice DDS bindings for Python and JavaScript: Python, Cython,
- Maintenance of Jenkins jobs for building packages for OpenSplice DDS components: Jenkins, CMake, Make, Bash
- Communicating with customers to address issues in the OpenSplice DDS software package

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Python
- C/C++
- Containers: Docker, Kubernetes
- Cloud: AWS EC2, Lambda
- Embedded development: cross-compilation, raspberry pi, nxp imx 6, assembly language
- Build systems: Jenkins, CMake, Make
- Software Engineering
- Test driven development
- Foundations in computer science